So, how would we use a service to
implement our application? Fortunately, we've already done most
of the work. We have a content provider
with a content notifier that will notify our
content observers. Our FetchWeatherTask already runs completely independently
of our UI. Good on us. Now, we
can make use of that Intent Service that
Rato mentioned earlier. With just a few small
changes, we can get our code working,
with an Intent Service, instead of with our
Fetch Weather task. To start, let's create a
new package for our service. [SOUND] Then we'll
add a new Java class in that package that extends inside Service. We hit Ctrl+I
to once again, add the required abstract method.
And Ctrl+O in order to add the constructor.
Since the service is an Android component, you guessed it, it needs to be in the
manifest. Okay, let's do this. Let's finish implementing the SunshineService
and call it from ForecastFragment. You can start a service using an intent with
the StartService method. It will help to remember how to use explicit intents.